welcome back, in this video we'll talk
欢迎回来 在本节我们将讨论
about how to compute derivatives for you
怎样计算偏导数
to implement gradient descent for
来实现逻辑回归的梯度下降算法
logistic regression. the key take aways
它的核心关键点是
will be what you need to implement that
其中有几个重要的公式
are the key equations you need in order
用来实现关于逻辑回归的
to implement gradient descent for
梯度下降算法
logistic regression. but in this video I
但是在本节视频中
want to do this computation using the
我将使用 导数计算图 的方式来计算梯度
computation graph. I have to admit using
虽然使用导数计算图
the computation graph is a little bit of
来计算逻辑回归的梯度下降
an overkill for deriving gradient
有点大材小用了
descent for logistic regression. but I
但是 我认为
want to start explaining things this way
以这种方式来讲解
to get you familiar with these ideas. so
可以更好地理解梯度下降
that hopefully you'll make a bit more
从而在讨论神经网络时 可以
sense when we talk about full fledged
更深刻而全面地
neural networks
理解神经网络
so let's dive into gradient
接下来开始学习
descent for logistic regression. to recap
逻辑回归的梯度下降算法
we had set up logistic regression as
回想一下逻辑回归的公式
follows your predictions y hat is
y~定义如下 y~=a=sigma(z)
defined as follows where z is that and
其中的z=w^T*x+b
if we focus on just one example for now
现在只考虑单个样本的情况
then the loss or respect to that one
关于该样本的损失函数定义如下
example is defined as follows where a is
L(a,y)=-(ylog(a)+(1-y)log(1-a)) 其中a是
the output of the logistic regression and y
逻辑回归的输出 y是
is the ground truth label so let's write
样本的标签值 现在写出该样本的
this out as a computation graph and for
偏导数计算图
this example let's say we have only two
假设样本只有两个
features x1 and x2. so in order to
特征x1和x2 为了
compute z, we'll need to input w1 w2 and
计算z 我们需要输入参数w1 w2 和 b
b in addition to the feature values x1
再包括样本特征值x1 x2
x2 so these things in a computation
因此用来计算z的
graph get used to compute z which is w1
偏导数计算公式
x1 plus w2 x2 plus b. draw a rectangle
z=w1*x1+w2*x2+b (如图用长方形括
box around that and then we compute y
起来了) 然后计算 y~
hat or a equals Sigma of Z that's the
或者 a 等于sigma(z) 也就是
next step in a computation graph and
偏导数计算图的下一步
then finally we compute L(a,y) and I
最后计算L(a,y)
won't copy the formula again so in
我不会再写出这个公式了
logistic regression what we want to do
因此在逻辑回归中我们需要做的是
is to modify the parameters w and b in
变换参数 w 和 b 的值
order to reduce this loss
来最小化损失函数函数L(a,y)
we've described before propagation steps
在前面我们已经讲解了一步一步
of how you actually compute the loss on
在单个训练样本上计算损失函数函数
a single training example now let's talk
现在让我们来
about how you can go backwards to talk
讨论怎样向后
to compute the derivatives here's the
计算偏导数 给出
cleaned up version of the diagram
的初始表达式如下z=w1*x1+w2*x2+b
because what we want to do is compute
要想计算损失函数L(a,y)
derivatives respect to this loss the
的偏导数
first thing we want to do we're going
首先我们要
backwards is to compute the derivative
向前一步先计算
of this loss with respect to the script
(dL(a,y)/da) 这是损失函数L
over there with respect to this variable
关于 变量a 的偏导数
a and so in the code you know you just
而在(Python)代码中你只需要
use da right to denote this variable
使用 da 来表示(dL(a,y)/da)
and it turns out that if you are
事实上如果你
familiar with calculus you can show that
熟悉微积分 偏导数 dL(a,y)/da 的
this ends up being negative y over a
最终结果是 -y/a
plus one minus y over one minus a and
加上 (1-y)/(1-a)
the way you do that is you take the
代价函数的偏导数计算公式
formula for the loss and if you are familiar
就是这样 并且如果你对
with calculus you can compute the
微积分熟悉的话 你计算
derivative with respect to the variable
的关于 变量a 的
lowercase a and you get this formula but
偏导数就是公式dL(a,y)=(-y/a)+(1-y/1-a)
if you're not familiar of calculus don't
如果你不熟悉微积分
worry about it we'll provide the
也不必太担心 我们会列出本课程
derivative formulas you need through out
涉及的所有求导公式
this course so if you are a expert in
因此 如果你非常熟悉微积分
calculus you'll encourage you to look up
我们鼓励你主动
the formula for the loss from their
推导前面介绍的损失函数的求导公式
previous slide and try to get director
使用微积分直接求出
for respect to a using you know calculus
L(a,y)关于变量a的偏导数
but if you don't know enough calculus to
如果你不太了解微积分
do that don't worry about it
也不用太担心
now having computed this quantity or da
现在计算出 da
the derivative of your final output
关于变量a 的最终结果
variable respect to a you can then go
现在可以再向后一步
backwards and it turns out that you can
计算dz 你可以认为
show dz which this is the Python code
dz就是Python(一种编程语言)代码
variable name this is going to be you
中的变量名
know the derivative of the loss with
dz是代价函数关于z的偏导数(dL/dz)
respect to z or for L you can really write
对于dL 可以写成
the loss including a and y explicitly as
dL(a,y) 显式地包含L
parameters or not right give either type
的参数a 和 y 这两种形式
of notation is equally acceptable they
dL/dz 或者 dL(a,y)/dz 都是正确的
can show that this is equal to a minus y
它们(dL/dz)求导的结果等于 a-y
just a couple comments only for those
稍微给熟悉微积分的人
of you did a experts in
解释一下
calculus if you're not explain calculus
如果你对微积分不熟悉
don't worry about it but it turns out
也不用担心
that this right dL dz this can be
实际上 dL/dz 等于
expressed as dL da time
(dL/da)*(da/dz)
da dz and it turns out that da dz
并且da/dz
this turns out to be a times 1 minus a
等于a*(1-a)
and dL da we are previously worked out
而 dL/da 在前面已经计算过了
over here and so if you take these two
因此将这两项
quantities dL da which is this
dL/da 即这部分
term together with da dz which is this
和 da/dz 这部分
term and just take these two things and
进行相乘
multiply them you can show that you the
最终的公式
equation simplifies the a minus y so
化简成 (a-y)
that's how you derive it and this is
这个推导的过程
really the chain rule that I briefly
就是我之前提到过的"链式法则"(一种求导法则)
clue to you before ok so feel free to go
如果你对微积分熟悉
through that calculation yourself if you
放心地去推导
are knowledgeable calculus but if you
整个求导过程
aren't all you need to know is that you
如果不熟悉微积分 你只需要知道
can compute dz as a minus y and it
dz 等于 (a-y)
already done the calculus for you and
已经计算好了
then the final step in back propagation
现在最后一步向后推导
is to go back to compute how much you
就是变化 w 和 b这两个参数
need to change w and b so in particular
来计算出新的L函数 特别地
you can show that the derivative respect
损失函数L关于w1的偏导数
to w1 and will call this DW 1 that
dL/dw1 写成 dw1
this is equal to x1 times dz
等于x1*dz
and then similarly dw 2 which is how
同样地 dw2 写成 w2
much you want to change w2 is x2 times
的变化量 dw2等于 x2*dz
dz and b excuse me db is equal to dz so
b 不好意思应该是 db 等于dz
if you want to do gradient descents with
因此关于单个样本的
respect to just this one example what
梯度下降算法
you will do is the following you would
你所需要做的就是这些事情
use this formula to compute dz and then
使用公式dz=(a-y)计算dz
use these formulas to compute dw1 dw2
使用dw1=x1*dz计算dw1 dw2=x2*dz计算dw2
and db and then you perform these
db=dz来计算db 然后
updates w1 gets updated w1 - learning
更新w1为w1减去学习率乘以dw1(w1:=w1-alpha*dw1)
rate alpha times dw1 w2 gets updated
类似地更新w2:=w2-alpha*dw2
similarly and B gets set as b - the
更新b为b减去学习率乘以db
learning rate times db and so this will
(b:=b-alpha*db) 这就是
be one step of gradicent descent with respect to a
关于单个样本实例的一次梯度更新步骤
single example so you've seen how to
现在你已经知道了
compute derivatives and implement
怎样计算导数并且实现
gradient descent for logistic regression
针对单个训练样本的
with respect to a single training
逻辑回归的梯度下降算法
example but to train logistic
但是训练逻辑回归模型
regression model you have not just one
不仅仅只有一个训练样本
training example given entire training
而是有m个训练样本的整个训练集
set of m training examples so
in the next video let's see how you can
因此在下一节视频中 我们将
take these ideas and apply them to
这些想法(知识点)应用到
learning not just from one example but
整个训练样本集中 而不仅仅只是
from an entire training set
单个样本上